Rich Crumley

Adabas DBA

rich.crumley@gmail.com

Summary

Richard is a skilled, Sr. Database Administrator/Engineer with over 30 years experience with Software AG products. His background includes installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes.

Richard's background also includes both technical and non-technical presentations and training. He has the ability to present technical information in an easy to understand format.

Experience

Adabas DBA at Southwest Airlines

April 2015 - Present

Rich is an Adabas DBA. His job involves installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes

Adabas DBA (consultant with NTT Data Americas) at Morgan Stanley

February 2003 - April 2015 (12 years 3 months)

Rich is an Adabas DBA. His job involves installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes. While at Morgan Stanley, Rich became the Adabas Operations Manager overseeing a staff of five DBAs. Part of his duties included the planning and execution of maintenance of over 40 production databases. This was in a multi-LPAR, multi-nucleus environment using Adabas Cluster Services and Adabas Parallel Services.

Senior Principal Consultant at NTT DATA Americas

February 2001 - April 2015 (14 years 3 months)

Adabas DBA

Adabas DBA

2001 - 2003 (3 years)

As an Adabas DBA, his job involves installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes

Adabas DBA (consultant with Cylogix) at Lehman Brothers

2001 - 2003 (3 years)

Adabas DBA

Advisory Instructor at Software AG

1999 - 2001 (3 years)

Teach Adabas courses with emphasis in Adabas Internals and Adabas Performance & Tuning

Staff Systems Specialist - Adabas DBA

1989 - 1998 (10 years)

His job involves installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes

Adabas DBA at Sprint

1988 - 1989 (2 years)

His job involves installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes

Adabas DBA

November 1985 - May 1988 (2 years 7 months)

As an Adabas DBA, his job involves installing, maintaining, supporting, debugging and tuning Software AG products on IBM Mainframes

SSgt at United States Marine Corps

September 1977 - December 1985 (8 years 4 months)

My first enlistment I was in the Infantry (0311) then I reenlisted and became a computer programmer (4063).

Education

Nazarene Bible College

BA, Ministry, 1989 - 2010

Nazarene Bible College

AA, Biblical Studies, 1989 - 1992

Rich Crumley

Adabas DBA

rich.crumley@gmail.com



Contact Rich on LinkedIn